

Aurora CO. United States

【(+1) 559-536-0231 | ■ timothyportnoff@gmail.com | ☑ timothyportnoff | 面 timothyportnoff

Summary_

Google certified technical professional with an extensive background in personal devices, networks, cybersecurity, and programming. Hands-on experience with troubleshooting, building computers, developing and deploying servers, experimenting on my RPi 4 homelab, working with teams, and building customer relationships. Currently I am actively pursuing a CompTIA A+ certification through IBM's preparation course.

Skills

Computer Science Artificial Intelligence

Information Technology Operating Systems, Troubleshooting, System Imaging, Log Analysis, Cybersecurity, Virtual Machines Github, Vim, Bash, C++, C, Python, HTML, PHP, Java, XeTeX, Data Structures, OOP, Arduino, RPi Prompt Engineering, Voice Synthesis, Speech Recognition, Stable Latent Diffusion, API Scripting

Experience __

OurPetDr

CLOUD SYSTEMS ADMIN

Jul. 2024 - Present

- Developed and deployed a virtual instance for the operations of a global Veterinarian company. To be compliant with PCI data security standards I had to register a FQDN, install TLS/SSL certs, and follow basic security measures such as disabling weak ciphers, disabling root access from the web, and banning brute-force ssh attempts.
- · Significantly sped up the invoicing and subscriptions by implementing a pipeline to automate the tedious process of assigning pet owners with Veterinarians by intercepting webhooks sent from the Stripe API.

Outlier AI

DATA ANNOTATION TECH

Oct. 2023 - Mar. 2024

- · Compared AI code execution and output for safety, accuracy, and fulfillment. Used Google Data Compute to complete data entry tasks like rating and explaining AI model performances in comparison with one another. Analyzed autonomous vehicle data to identify pedestrians, vehicles, and hazards with LiDAR. Trained an AI to detect and distinguish veins, arteries, stents, and blood clots in the human body by annotating catheter footage frame by frame.
- Used Slack to develop leadership through communication and troubleshooting with 500K community members. As the community grew rapidly, issues and questions went overlooked. I enjoyed helping team members struggling with AI projects and conversing as a team to decide project outcomes.

Costco Wholesale

SALES ASSOCIATE

Nov. 2017 - Mar. 2023

- · Sales required technical knowledge about our entire device inventory. I would help members with personal device issues, decide between tech products, track terminal inventory, track member information, place & support members over the phone, cashier and count money, audit jewelry, and manage the photo center queue and inventory.
- · Learned that enthusiasm and communication are needed to work efficiently with others, and customer experience requires listening and a positive attitude. Because of my work ethic, I was the first person relied on to complete special projects.

Education

AI Essentials Certificate

GOOGLE

Oct. 2024

Integrated AI into generative workflows with responsible AI principles, engineering & optimizing prompts, and experience with 10+ AI tools.

IT Support Professional Certificate

Sep. 2024

GOOGLE

• Mastered IT foundations such as networking, operating systems, system administration, encryption, security, and permissions.

A.S. in Information Technology

Dec. 2023

CLOVIS COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Programming Concepts and Methodology, Computer Architecture, Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science, & Data Structures Visualization

High School Diploma Madera, California

LIBERTY HIGH SCHOOL Mar. 2017

• Architecture, Construction, & Engineering (ACE), Regional Occupational Programs (ROP) such as ROP Robotics & ROP Digital Media